Register of the Russkii rybolovno-okhotnichii klub Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Russkii rybolovno-okhotnichii klub records,
1940-1989
2001C9
Russkii rybolovno-okhotnichii klub
1 microfilm reel (0.15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Minutes, correspondence, lists, financial records, and photographs, relating to Russian-American hunting and fishing in the United States.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2001.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Originals
Originals in: Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco.
Administrative History
Russian-American rod and gun club.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of the records of the Russian Rod and Gun Club, a non-profit organization, whose primary purpose was to unite those who are interested in fishing, hunting and related sports and to promote said sports by sponsoring contests and competitions. The collection also includes photographs of members of the Club and their social activities.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Russians--United States.; Hunting--United States.; Fishing--United States.; Russia.; United States.
Series Description
- Office File, 1940-1989. (Box 1)
  Correspondence, financial documents, founding documents, liquidation documents, membership lists, minutes of meetings, printed matter, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- Photographs, 1943-1978 and undated. (Box 2)
  31 prints, 8 negatives, primarily of the club's social activities, fishing, and of its members
Container List
- OFFICE FILE, 1940-1989 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1988. (Folder 1: 1)
    Includes letters of one of the founders of the club, P. Klikoff, cards, and thank you notes
  - Financial records
    - General, 1967-1989. (Folder 1: 2)
      Includes receipts, checking account statements, business property statement
    - Profit and loss reports, 1953-1987 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Fish registration book, 1960-1984. (Folder 1: 4)
    Includes list of club fishing champions, 1940-1970
  - Founding documents, 1942 (Folder 1: 5)
  - Liquidation documents, 1986 (Folder 1: 6)
  - Membership lists, 1940-1987 (Folder 1: 7)
  - Minutes of meetings.
    Includes memoranda and reports
    - 1971-1981 (Folder 1: 8)
    - 1982-1988 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Printed matter
    - Clippings (Folder 1: 10)
    - Flyers relating to purchase of club house (Folder 1: 11)
    - Programs of concert-balls, 1950-1956 (Folder 1: 12)
    - Scrapbook. (Folder 1: 13)
      Includes articles about the Russian community in the United States and the Russian Center in San Francisco
  - Subject file - Anniversary dinners, 1950-1987 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Miscellany. (Folder 1: 15)
    Includes one issue of the newspaper Russkii Invalid, 1967 May. Also includes drafts of newspaper articles relating to the club and its members
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1943-1978 and undated. (Box 2)
  31 prints, 8 negatives, primarily of the club's social activities and its members
  - Negatives (Folder 2: 1)
  - Prints (Folder 2: 2)